The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal\NSubtitles by Bonobosubs\Nhttps://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
Where is the Fighting Evil Sect Leader ?
Teleportation ?
A Nascent Soul cultivator !
Duanmu Ji\NEight Extremes Devil Lord\NDevil Lord of Qi Mei City\NMiddle stage Soul Formation
Are you the Sect Leader ?
No, no, no !
I am merely his disciple !
So where is he ?
Master has my Soul Blood...
If I reveal his location,
it will be the end for me.
Master...
Master, he...
is traveling far away...
You don't get to decide
whether you speak or not.
Found him.
I hope he'll survive.
If he doesn't, I'll die along with him...
Even with Ma Liang's talented body,
I don't have high hopes of forming a Nascent Soul.
In his memories,
I saw that the Divine Path
of the War God Shrine is a method to form a Nascent Soul.
It would be a shame if I didn't use Ma Liang's identity
to have a glimpse.
Disciple Ma Liang
requests to view the Divine Path.
Identity token.
You can enter.
Wait !
Greetings, Ancestor.
In just a few years,
he actually reached Core Formation ?
The Divine Path
is the secret technique of our War God Shrine.
Are you aware ?
Disciple is aware.
What's the meaning of a secret technique ?
It mustn't be revealed to outsiders.
The Divine Path is profound and mysterious.
It's very beneficial for forming a Nascent Soul.
But this is our War God Hall's secret technique.
A mere Core Formation brat
coveting the Divine Path
should weigh whether he has the capability.
Do you think the Founder of our War God Shrine
will accept you ?
Disciple understands
what Ancestor means.
He's just a rogue cultivator.
So what if he reached Core Formation ?
It seems that
this will take some more scheming...
Little guy,
this old man has finally found you !
This person's cultivation is far above mine.
Who is he ?
Could he be the Ancestor of someone I killed in the Sea of Devils
that's seeking revenge ?
He doesn't have good intentions.
Little guy,
this formation can't protect you.
This formation was made by all the Ancestors of the Burning Fire Alliance
but he easily broke it.
This person's cultivation is truly unfathomable...
Fellow cultivator,
why did you destroy our formation !?
Scram !
Senior is the Devil Lord of Qi Mei City.
A Soul Formation Senior !
This is the last warning.
Let me pass.
He vanished !?
How could the connection to the Soul Blood vanish ?
You absolutely cannot escape my grasp !
What is this Senior doing ?
Divine Sense Lockdown !
This is the signature formation of the Eight Extremes Devil Lord, Duanmu Ji.
From now on, every cultivator entering or leaving Xuanwu
will be under his watch.
Little guy,
I, the Eight Extremes Devil Lord,
will refine the entire country of Xuanwu if I need to
until I find you !
What do we do now ?
Nothing...
Whoever the Eight Extremes Devil Lord is looking for
probably won't survive.
This person's cultivation is high
and he has ill intent.
For now, I am completely powerless to resist him.
The only option now is to find a flaw in his formation
and escape this place !
3 years later
Little Lin,
you can't stay infinitely in the Heaven Defying Bead.
If all these crystals are dim
and the space turns completely black
you will never be able to leave anymore.
If you ever reach that point,
you must stay outside for 3 full days
before you can enter again.
I have looked for 3 years
but only found a single flaw in this formation.
However,
it could very well be a trap.
Enough,
I'll risk it !
How did a mere Core Formation brat do this ?
Completely concealing your aura like that
is truly unbelievable.
Little guy,
I have been waiting for you for 3 years !
How could I be worth
3 years of Senior's time ?
Die !
Why is there no Divine Sense ?
It's said the Death Spell
attacks using Divine Sense.
Senior went through such trouble to capture me.
What do you want from me ?
How do you know
I'm not here to kill you ?
With your cultivation,
you could've killed me in an instant.
But you went to great lengths
to trap me like that.
You...
need something from me !
Interesting, interesting...
What's your name ?
Ma Liang
Ma Liang,
do you
know the Death Spell ?
So he mistook the Ji Realm
for the Death Spell.
Little guy, don't be nervous.
This old man merely wishes to borrow your Death Spell
in order to obtain treasures.
If you agree to accompany me,
I'll give you an Earth Transformation Pill and a Nascent Soul Formation Pill.
You're quite composed for a brat.
This Earth Transformation pill
will help you go from Early to Middle stage Core Formation
with a very high success rate.
This Nascent Soul Formation Pill is even more remarkable.
It's a rare pill that can increase the chance of forming a Nascent Soul.
The recipe for this pill
is only held by rank 5 countries.
I want to know
how dangerous the place we're going to is.
I won't hide it from you
Even if Peak Late stage Nascent Soul cultivators enter it,
they might not make it out alive.
If you're not very careful,
death is inevitable.
But
even if that place is very dangerous,
the rewards are also immense.
Artifacts, pills, spells,
it has everything !
Besides that,
there should even be a Soul Transformation Pill.
With a single pill,
you have a chance
to leap directly to Soul Transformation.
So generous ?
The stakes must be high.
You need not worry
about how dangerous it is.
Your Death Spell
will be of great use in a particular trial.
This old man
will definitely ensure your safety.
If I refuse
he will kill me on the spot.
But 2 pills
are not enough.
If it weren't for the rules of that place
I would have used a restriction
to control you, kid.
This is a Divine Sense mark
to prevent you from disappearing again.
Once we reach that place,
I will naturally remove it.
Who is in charge here ?
What's happening ?
Such a powerful pressure !
Let's see.
The Eight Extremes Devil Lord was looking
for him !?
Since Senior graces us with his presence,
might I ask how we can help you ?
My little friend here is quite interested in your Divine Path.
I wonder if he might have a look ?
This...
The Divine Path is the secret technique of our War God Shrine.
Senior...
I hate asking favors !
It's too troublesome.
I'll just level this sect instead !
Thank you Senior for the reminder.
Ma Liang is indeed a disciple of our War God Shrine.
He is allowed to see the Divine Path at Core Formation.
Ma Liang,
come with me.
Little friend,
I will wait for you outside.
If anything happens to you,
I will make sure every single person here
is buried alongside you !
Ancestor !
Wang Lin,
I forgave you for what happened.
No matter how much trouble you're in,
don't involve our War God Shrine anymore.
If you promise that to me,
I'll open the hall for you
to let you see the Divine Path.
Senior can rest assured.
I will leave after viewing the Divine Path.
and will never return.
This technique is very profound.
Not everyone is fated to learn it.
Or rather
only a very few people
are fated.
What do you mean ?
You'll understand when you see it.
In the novel, the events of the this episode and the previous happen in a different order. Wang Lin doesn't go back to the Fighting Evil Sect after escorting Li Muwan to the Luo River Sect. In fact, the reason he hurries to send her off and refuses to stay with her is because he sensed that he was being chased by Duanmu Ji through a wisp of Divine Sense that he left behind him. He didn't want her to be endangered.\N\NThe Eight Extremes of conceptual elaboration are a philosophical concept of buddhism. Here is the list :\N- arising\N- ceasing\N- being non-existent\N- being permanent\N- coming\N- going\N- being multiple\N- being single
Count the specks of time
floating down gently.
The carving knife in your hands etches out destiny.
Forever lock away the scars
of this mortal life.
This fleeting youth is a thing of the past.
The flying bird could not escape the twilight
that fills the sky with a myriad of colors.
The night-blooming flower cannot drink
the crystalization of the golden wind and the jade dew.
I will ask the heavens who exactly
sliced open this world
to let the rain fall in.
I will refine the world
to make our palm lines say
that we will live forever.
Walking off the beaten path
through heaven and earth.
Before returning to dust,
I will refine this mortal body.
The left shore is the joyous laughter
that can brighten up a thousand years of sadness.
The right shore is an eternal silence
lingering under the candlelight.
To overturn this fate,
I will walk against the heavens.
I will even gather the clouds
to illuminate the sky for you.
All this sadness was not meaningless.
How many lives and deaths\Nhave passed in the blink of an eye ?
I vow to break
this chess game of fate.